<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-18T14:10:48+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">thoughts, projects, interests</title><subtitle>academic life from the point of view of the student, projects, interests, and many things that I experienced.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to build websites on GitHub Pages with jekyll(Will be completed soon)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/11/18/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to build websites on GitHub Pages with jekyll(Will be completed soon)" /><published>2017-11-18T11:39:58+03:00</published><updated>2017-11-18T11:39:58+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/11/18/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/11/18/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi Everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to share my experience about building websites on &lt;strong&gt;Github Pages&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;jekyll&lt;/strong&gt;. Actually, I have a website on Wordpress in Turkish. But also I wanted to build another one in English to improve my English writing skill and make my contents public not local. And then, I searched for platform for my website. I didn’t want to use Wordpress again because I experienced it. So I decided to try another one.While I was searhing, I found GitHub Pages. It gives you hosting for your website and project website from your repository.That’s perfect !. So I decided to build my website with GitHub Pages.And I learned Github Pages support a thing named jekyll. I didn’t know what “jekyll” is . After a quick search, I learned &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;jekyll&quot; is a blog-aware, static site generator in Ruby&lt;/code&gt;. Waitt What ? What is the meaning of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;blog-aware&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;static site generator&lt;/code&gt; ? So, Let’s learn these terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blog-aware-&quot;&gt;blog-aware ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;One of Jekyll’s best aspects is that it is “blog aware”. What does this mean, exactly? Well, simply put, it means that blogging is baked into Jekyll’s functionality. If you write articles and publish them online, you can publish and maintain a blog simply by managing a folder of text-files on your computer. Compared to the hassle of configuring and maintaining databases and web-based CMS systems, this will be a welcome change!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definition from jekyll offical &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/posts/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;static-site-generator-&quot;&gt;static site generator ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A static site generator takes source files and generates an entirely static website.&lt;/code&gt; from quite easy to understand content on &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.cloudcannon.com/jekyll/why-use-a-static-site-generator/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and also there are videos about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is enough for now. I will add also how I build this website later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enes Köksalmış.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hi Everyone,</summary></entry></feed>